To build anything that truly lasts, it
takes time.
We spoke uh to the CFO of ICIC Alumbad,
Mr. Gopal Balachchandran on their
premium growth after posting a mixed set
of quarter 1 numbers. That stock
currently holding up smartly. Let's go
across and listen in to what he had to
say and stay tuned of course for the
full chat right here on ET now.
>> The general insurance industry reported
a combined ratio of 112%.
that effectively means that you're
losing 12 rupees to every 100 rupees of
premium that you have collected. So
hence to that extent the industry has
been exhibiting losses and therefore to
that extent the market has remained
relatively competitive. In the backdrop
of that, I think from an ICL Lombard
standpoint, what we have largely stuck
to is to drive and pick profitable risk
selections and that is the reason we
have been able to grow in segments which
we think has been viable from our own
underwriting and our own pricing
standpoint but has been happy to kind of
be a bit guarded and cautious on
segments where we have seen elevated
levels of competitive intensity. So
hence the growth has to be viewed in the
context of uh where the market is
currently operating at and there again
uh even in the past when we have spoken
we have always said that relative to the
industry combined IC alumbarts combined
has been significantly better uh
particularly let's say for the year gone
by when I said the industry is operating
at 112%. We ended the last year with a
combined of roughly about 102%
thereabout so even last year we had a
difference of almost close to 10%. uh
relative to the industry combined
numbers and therefore what we will kind
of closely watch for is how the industry
responds particularly with respect to
the pricing environment and on that
basis on the preferred segments we will
continue to exhibit uh significant
outperformance on growth and on segments
where the markets gets very aggressive
we will be guarded and cautious
>> okay so that's a take coming in from the
management of IC lumbard gopal All by